<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CyberSec Intelligence Feed</title>
    <link>https://cybersec-intelligence.com</link>
    <description>Top 10 cybersecurity news focused on executive decision-making</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:05:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cybersec-intelligence.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Iran-Linked RedKitten Cyber Campaign Targets Human Rights NGOs and Activists]]></title>
      <category>IAM/Zero Trust/Geopolitics</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b95795be-98a5-43f0-8a05-afa3c0216929</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>An Iran-linked threat actor, RedKitten, is actively targeting human rights NGOs and activists, particularly those documenting abuses related to recent nationwide unrest in Iran. This campaign, observed in January 2026, leverages Farsi-speaking operatives to compromise targets.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations involved in human rights advocacy, journalism, or those with personnel operating in politically sensitive regions face significant reputational damage, data loss, and potential operational disruption. This also highlights the growing risk of state-sponsored cyber espionage against non-traditional targets.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The campaign is driven by Iranian state interests, likely aiming to suppress dissent, gather intelligence on opposition movements, and disrupt efforts to document human rights violations. The timing coincides with internal unrest, suggesting a direct response to perceived threats to the regime.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Implement enhanced security awareness training for employees, especially those in high-risk roles or regions, focusing on phishing and social engineering. Strengthen identity and access management (IAM) with multi-factor authentication (MFA) and consider adopting a Zero Trust architecture to limit lateral movement in case of a breach.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/iran-linked-redkitten-cyber-campaign.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Mandiant Finds ShinyHunters-Style Vishing Attacks Stealing MFA to Breach SaaS Platforms]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">802b7aa5-3eff-4c8c-ba9f-b9fdac573ccc</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Mandiant has identified an increase in sophisticated vishing attacks, consistent with the ShinyHunters group, targeting organizations. These attacks employ voice phishing and fake credential harvesting sites to bypass multi-factor authentication (MFA) and gain unauthorized access to SaaS platforms. The primary goal appears to be data exfiltration and subsequent extortion.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses face significant financial and reputational risks due to potential data breaches, intellectual property theft, and operational disruptions. The compromise of SaaS platforms can lead to widespread data loss, regulatory fines, and a loss of customer trust, impacting long-term business viability.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The attacks exploit human vulnerabilities through social engineering (vishing) and leverage convincing fake login pages to trick users into divulging credentials and MFA codes. The increasing reliance on SaaS platforms and the sophistication of these phishing techniques contribute to the effectiveness of these breaches.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Implement robust employee training programs focused on identifying vishing and sophisticated phishing attempts, emphasizing the importance of verifying communication channels. Deploy advanced MFA solutions that are resistant to phishing, such as FIDO2-based security keys, and enhance endpoint detection and response (EDR) capabilities to quickly identify and neutralize suspicious activity.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/mandiant-finds-shinyhunters-using.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CERT Polska Details Coordinated Cyber Attacks on 30+ Wind and Solar Farms]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dcb03f3a-235e-46d1-b535-ac6551f0bb5f</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>CERT Polska reported coordinated cyber attacks on over 30 wind and solar farms, a manufacturing company, and a large combined heat and power plant on December 29, 2025. These attacks targeted critical infrastructure and a private sector entity in Poland. The incident highlights a significant threat to operational technology (OT) environments.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>This incident demonstrates the potential for widespread disruption to critical energy infrastructure, leading to power outages and economic losses. For the manufacturing sector, such attacks can halt production, cause financial damage, and erode customer trust. The coordinated nature suggests a sophisticated adversary capable of impacting multiple sectors simultaneously.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The attacks likely exploited vulnerabilities within the operational technology (OT) systems of these critical infrastructure entities. The coordination across multiple targets suggests a well-resourced and strategic attacker, potentially leveraging supply chain weaknesses or common system vulnerabilities. Specific root causes or exploited vulnerabilities are not detailed but are typical in such sophisticated attacks.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Executives should prioritize comprehensive cybersecurity assessments of all OT/ICS environments, including third-party suppliers. Implement robust network segmentation, multi-factor authentication, and continuous monitoring for anomalous activity. Develop and regularly test incident response plans specifically tailored for OT/ICS environments to minimize downtime and recovery costs.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/poland-attributes-december-cyber.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Researchers Uncover Chrome Extensions Abusing Affiliate Links and Stealing ChatGPT Access]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ef966ea0-1adc-4604-b105-c75166c960be</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Malicious Google Chrome extensions, such as 'Amazon Ads Blocker,' have been identified hijacking affiliate links, exfiltrating user data, and stealing OpenAI ChatGPT authentication tokens. These extensions, disguised as legitimate tools, compromise user privacy and financial interests through surreptitious activities.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses face significant reputational damage if their employees' compromised accounts are used for malicious activities or if sensitive company data is exfiltrated. Financial losses can occur through affiliate link hijacking, diverting revenue, and potential legal liabilities from data breaches.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The incident stems from users installing seemingly innocuous browser extensions that contain hidden malicious functionalities. The lack of stringent vetting for extensions in app stores and users' trust in advertised features contribute to the successful deployment and operation of these threats.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Implement strict policies regarding browser extension installations, recommending only pre-approved and vetted extensions. Conduct regular security awareness training for employees on the risks of untrusted software and the importance of verifying extension legitimacy before installation.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/researchers-uncover-chrome-extensions.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[China-Linked UAT-8099 Targets IIS Servers in Asia with BadIIS SEO Malware]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">34f686a1-9766-4c73-9cad-0a2300fb9acf</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>A China-linked threat actor, UAT-8099, launched a campaign between late 2025 and early 2026, targeting vulnerable Internet Information Services (IIS) servers in Asia. The attack, discovered by Cisco Talos, primarily focused on organizations in Thailand and Vietnam, deploying 'BadIIS SEO malware'.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations in affected regions, particularly those using IIS servers, face significant reputational damage and potential financial losses due to compromised websites and data breaches. The SEO malware could degrade search engine rankings, impacting online visibility and customer acquisition for businesses.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The campaign exploited vulnerabilities in IIS servers, indicating a lack of timely patching and robust security configurations. UAT-8099 leveraged these weaknesses to inject malicious code, likely for SEO poisoning or further exploitation.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Mandate immediate patching and security audits of all IIS servers, especially those in Asian operations. Implement advanced threat detection and prevention systems to identify and block similar sophisticated attacks. Review and strengthen incident response plans to address potential future compromises effectively.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/china-linked-uat-8099-targets-iis.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[KiloView Encoder Series]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">58d9d760-96f3-4323-b263-55c39db396ef</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>A critical vulnerability (CVE-2026-1453) has been identified in multiple versions of KiloView Encoder Series devices. This flaw, categorized as 'Missing Authentication for Critical Function,' allows unauthenticated attackers to create or delete administrator accounts, leading to full administrative control.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing KiloView Encoder Series in their communications and IT infrastructure face a severe risk of unauthorized access and operational disruption. Successful exploitation could lead to data manipulation, system downtime, and significant reputational damage due to compromised critical systems.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerability stems from a critical function lacking proper authentication, allowing any unauthenticated attacker to bypass security controls and gain administrative privileges. KiloView has not yet provided a patch or mitigation, leaving affected systems exposed.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately identify and isolate all KiloView Encoder Series devices within the network. Implement robust network segmentation and firewall rules to minimize external exposure, and consider alternative, more secure methods for remote access, such as updated VPNs, while monitoring for any suspicious activity.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-029-01</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rockwell Automation ArmorStart LT]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">28405f5a-8d69-4c30-a722-0b39a0c20c92</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Multiple high-severity denial-of-service (DoS) vulnerabilities (CVE-2025-9464, CVE-2025-9465, CVE-2025-9466, CVE-2025-9278, CVE-2025-9279, CVE-2025-9280, CVE-2025-9281, CVE-2025-9282, CVE-2025-9283) have been identified in Rockwell Automation ArmorStart LT devices, versions <=V2.002. These vulnerabilities, primarily categorized as Uncontrolled Resource Consumption, can be exploited remotely to render devices unresponsive or cause unexpected reboots, leading to operational disruptions.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Successful exploitation of these vulnerabilities could lead to significant operational downtime in critical manufacturing environments globally, as these devices are widely deployed. Businesses face potential financial losses from production halts, equipment damage, and reputational damage due to service interruptions. The lack of an immediate patch means organizations must rely on mitigation strategies, increasing operational risk.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from security issues within the ArmorStart LT firmware, specifically related to how the devices handle network traffic and grammar tests (e.g., CIP fuzzing, Achilles tests, Burp Suite scans). These actions trigger uncontrolled resource consumption or unexpected reboots, indicating weaknesses in the device's resilience to malformed or excessive network inputs.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Executive leadership should ensure immediate implementation of CISA's recommended defensive measures, including minimizing network exposure of control systems, isolating OT networks with firewalls, and securing remote access via updated VPNs. Furthermore, conduct a thorough risk assessment and impact analysis for all deployed ArmorStart LT devices to understand potential exposure and prioritize mitigation efforts until a patch is available. Engage with Rockwell Automation for updates on patches and further guidance.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-029-02</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CISA Adds One Known Exploited Vulnerability to Catalog]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">719f0bcf-578a-4cfb-8f6d-5651481ce0d7</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>CISA has added a new vulnerability, CVE-2026-1281, affecting Ivanti Endpoint Manager Mobile (EPMM) to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) Catalog. This code injection vulnerability is actively being exploited by malicious cyber actors, posing a significant risk to federal and other organizations. The inclusion in the KEV Catalog mandates remediation for Federal Civilian Executive Branch (FCEB) agencies.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing Ivanti EPMM are at immediate risk of compromise, potentially leading to data breaches, operational disruptions, and reputational damage. Failure to remediate this vulnerability can result in significant financial losses due to incident response, recovery efforts, and potential regulatory fines. For FCEB agencies, non-compliance with BOD 22-01 carries regulatory implications.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerability, CVE-2026-1281, is a code injection flaw within Ivanti EPMM, allowing attackers to execute arbitrary code. This type of vulnerability is a common attack vector due to its potential for remote exploitation and high impact. The active exploitation indicates that threat actors have successfully identified and weaponized this weakness.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately identify and patch all instances of Ivanti Endpoint Manager Mobile (EPMM) to mitigate CVE-2026-1281. Prioritize this remediation as part of your organization's vulnerability management program, even if not a federal agency, given the active exploitation. Additionally, review and enhance monitoring for suspicious activity related to Ivanti EPMM installations.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2026/01/29/cisa-adds-one-known-exploited-vulnerability-catalog</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rockwell Automation ControlLogix]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3f54577c-6531-42b9-89e9-72df67a4f124</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Rockwell Automation ControlLogix Redundancy Enhanced Modules (1756-RM2 and 1756-RM2XT) are vulnerable to multiple denial-of-service issues (CVE-2025-14027). These vulnerabilities, rated with a CVSS v3.1 score of 7.5 (High), can be triggered by crafted inputs, leading to device unresponsiveness and potential major nonrecoverable faults requiring a restart.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Successful exploitation could lead to significant operational disruptions and downtime in critical infrastructure sectors such as Chemical, Energy, and Manufacturing. The denial-of-service condition directly impacts the availability of control systems, potentially causing production halts, safety concerns, and financial losses due to interrupted operations.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from 'Missing Release of Memory after Effective Lifetime' (CWE-401) and other resource exhaustion scenarios within the firmware. This allows attackers to cause memory leaks and other issues through malformed Class 3 messages, ultimately leading to system instability and denial of service.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Organizations using affected Rockwell Automation ControlLogix modules should prioritize upgrading to the 1756-RM3. If an upgrade is not immediately feasible, implement robust security best practices, including minimizing network exposure, isolating control networks with firewalls, and securing remote access via updated VPNs.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-029-03</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Fortinet Releases Guidance to Address Ongoing Exploitation of Authentication Bypass Vulnerability CVE-2026-24858]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">0f49983f-cb90-4d40-870f-4950709f134b</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Fortinet has issued guidance regarding the active exploitation of CVE-2026-24858, an authentication bypass vulnerability affecting multiple Fortinet products when FortiCloud Single Sign-On (SSO) is enabled. This vulnerability allows malicious actors with a FortiCloud account to gain unauthorized access to other users' registered devices, even if previous SSO bypass vulnerabilities (CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719) were patched.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing vulnerable Fortinet products with FortiCloud SSO enabled face significant risks of unauthorized access, leading to potential data breaches, system compromise, and operational disruption. Malicious actors have been observed making unauthorized firewall configuration changes, creating new accounts, and altering VPN settings, which can severely impact network security and business continuity. The repeated nature of these SSO bypass vulnerabilities also poses a reputational risk to Fortinet and raises concerns about the security posture of their products.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The core issue is an authentication bypass vulnerability (CWE-288) within FortiCloud SSO, allowing an attacker to bypass login authentication. This new vulnerability persists despite patches for previous, related SSO bypasses (CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719), indicating a deeper architectural or implementation flaw in Fortinet's SSO mechanism. The exploitation relies on attackers having a FortiCloud account and a registered device, enabling them to leverage the bypass to access other users' devices.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately disable FortiCloud SSO authentication on all affected Fortinet devices until a verified patch is available and applied. Conduct a thorough forensic investigation for indicators of compromise on all internet-accessible Fortinet products to identify any unauthorized activity. Prioritize applying all available security updates and follow Fortinet's official guidance as soon as they are released to mitigate this critical vulnerability.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2026/01/28/fortinet-releases-guidance-address-ongoing-exploitation-authentication-bypass-vulnerability-cve-2026</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>