<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CyberSec Intelligence Feed</title>
    <link>https://cybersec-intelligence.com</link>
    <description>Top 10 cybersecurity news focused on executive decision-making</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 03:05:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cybersec-intelligence.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[ClawJacked Flaw Lets Malicious Sites Hijack Local OpenClaw AI Agents via WebSocket]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">09a134d3-63f9-4d17-b0ae-2c592c66c1f2</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>A high-severity vulnerability, dubbed 'ClawJacked Flaw,' was discovered and fixed in OpenClaw AI agents. This flaw allowed malicious websites to hijack locally running AI agents via WebSocket connections. The vulnerability was inherent to the core OpenClaw system, not requiring any plugins or extensions.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses utilizing OpenClaw AI agents faced significant operational and reputational risks, including potential data breaches, unauthorized AI agent manipulation, and disruption of critical AI-driven processes. Exploitation could lead to financial losses due to compromised operations and remediation efforts, as well as damage to customer trust.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The root cause was a fundamental security flaw within the OpenClaw gateway's core system, allowing unauthorized WebSocket connections from malicious sites. This indicates a potential oversight in the initial security design or implementation of the AI agent's communication protocols, failing to adequately validate or restrict external connections.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately verify that all OpenClaw AI agent deployments are updated to the patched version to mitigate the 'ClawJacked Flaw.' Conduct a comprehensive security audit of all AI/ML systems to identify and address similar inherent vulnerabilities. Implement robust network segmentation and access controls to restrict unauthorized external access to internal AI infrastructure.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/clawjacked-flaw-lets-malicious-sites.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Thousands of Public Google Cloud API Keys Exposed with Gemini Access After API Enablement]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 09:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b527db9a-f5bf-4b17-b0d3-c755594e2586</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Nearly 3,000 Google Cloud API keys, intended for billing identification, were found exposed in client-side code. These exposed keys could be exploited to authenticate to sensitive Gemini AI endpoints, potentially allowing unauthorized access to private data. This vulnerability emerged after the enablement of the Gemini API.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses utilizing Google Cloud and Gemini APIs face significant data breach risks, leading to potential regulatory fines, reputational damage, and loss of customer trust. Operational disruptions could occur as organizations scramble to revoke compromised keys and secure their AI integrations. Financial implications include costs associated with incident response, forensic analysis, and potential legal liabilities.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The core issue stems from the exposure of API keys in client-side code, a common security misconfiguration. The problem was exacerbated by Google's API design, which allowed these billing-oriented keys to authenticate to sensitive Gemini endpoints, a capability likely unintended or overlooked during API enablement. Lack of stringent access controls and key management practices contributed to the widespread exposure.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Mandate an immediate audit of all Google Cloud API key deployments to identify and revoke any keys exposed in client-side code. Implement robust API key management policies, including the use of service accounts, API key restrictions, and secret management solutions. Educate development teams on secure API key handling best practices and integrate automated scanning tools to detect exposed credentials proactively.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/thousands-of-public-google-cloud-api.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Pentagon Designates Anthropic Supply Chain Risk Over AI Military Dispute]]></title>
      <category>IAM/Zero Trust/Geopolitics</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4e29d415-a13f-4824-aab5-1c81e2d42f5c</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>The Pentagon has designated AI company Anthropic as a 'supply chain risk' following a dispute over the lawful use of its AI model, Claude. Anthropic refused to allow its AI to be used for mass domestic surveillance of Americans and fully autonomous weapons, leading to an impasse in negotiations.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>This designation could severely impact Anthropic's ability to secure government contracts and partnerships, potentially leading to significant revenue loss and reputational damage. It also sets a precedent for other AI companies regarding ethical considerations and military applications, influencing future business models and partnerships.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The core issue stems from a fundamental disagreement between Anthropic's ethical stance on AI usage (prohibiting mass surveillance and autonomous weapons) and the Pentagon's strategic interests. This highlights the growing tension between technological innovation, ethical AI development, and national security objectives.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Executives should re-evaluate their AI development and deployment strategies, ensuring clear ethical guidelines and use-case restrictions are established and communicated. Companies engaging with government entities must proactively address potential conflicts between ethical principles and national security requirements to mitigate supply chain risk designations.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/pentagon-designates-anthropic-supply.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[DoJ Seizes $61 Million in Tether Linked to Pig Butchering Crypto Scams]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d12dcc6a-3540-47a9-9111-da5c1e3f01f4</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>The U.S. Department of Justice (DoJ) successfully seized $61 million in Tether cryptocurrency directly linked to 'pig butchering' investment scams. These funds were identified in cryptocurrency addresses used for laundering proceeds stolen from victims of these fraudulent schemes.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>This incident highlights the persistent threat of sophisticated cryptocurrency scams, which can lead to significant financial losses for individuals and businesses. For financial institutions and cryptocurrency platforms, it underscores the reputational risk and potential regulatory scrutiny associated with facilitating transactions for illicit activities, even unknowingly.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The 'pig butchering' scams exploit human trust through elaborate social engineering tactics, often involving long-term grooming of victims. The use of cryptocurrency, specifically Tether, provides a perceived layer of anonymity and ease of transfer for criminals, making it a preferred method for laundering stolen funds.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Executives should prioritize enhanced employee and customer education on identifying and avoiding cryptocurrency investment scams. Implement robust anti-money laundering (AML) and know-your-customer (KYC) protocols, particularly for cryptocurrency transactions, to detect and prevent the flow of illicit funds. Collaborate with law enforcement and industry peers to share threat intelligence and best practices for combating financial fraud.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/doj-seizes-61-million-in-tether-linked.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[900+ Sangoma FreePBX Instances Compromised in Ongoing Web Shell Attacks]]></title>
      <category>Top Incident/Vulnerability</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ff0ef72b-3194-404d-86ef-22f6e94a3d1f</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Over 900 Sangoma FreePBX instances globally, including 401 in the U.S., remain compromised with web shells. These attacks exploited a command injection vulnerability, initially detected in December 2023, allowing unauthorized access and control over affected systems.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses utilizing FreePBX are at severe risk of data breaches, operational disruption, and reputational damage. The presence of web shells grants attackers persistent access, potentially leading to further exploitation, data exfiltration, or the use of compromised systems for other malicious activities.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The primary cause is the exploitation of a command injection vulnerability within Sangoma FreePBX systems. This indicates a failure in timely patching or an unaddressed security flaw that allowed attackers to execute arbitrary commands and install web shells.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately identify and patch all Sangoma FreePBX instances to mitigate the command injection vulnerability. Conduct thorough forensic analysis on all FreePBX systems to detect and remove any lingering web shells or backdoors, and implement enhanced monitoring for unusual activity on these systems.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/900-sangoma-freepbx-instances.html</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Chargemap chargemap.com]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2d133226-6491-419e-ac0d-2334961be39b</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Multiple critical and high-severity vulnerabilities have been identified in Chargemap chargemap.com, affecting all versions of their electric vehicle charging station management platform. These vulnerabilities, including missing authentication, improper restriction of authentication attempts, insufficient session expiration, and insufficiently protected credentials, could allow attackers to gain unauthorized administrative control over charging stations or disrupt services through denial-of-service attacks. Chargemap has not responded to CISA's requests for coordination regarding these issues.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Businesses relying on Chargemap's platform for EV charging infrastructure face significant operational risks, including potential service outages, unauthorized control of charging stations, and data corruption. This could lead to financial losses from disrupted services, reputational damage due to unreliable charging, and potential liability if compromised stations cause harm or data breaches. The lack of vendor response exacerbates the risk, leaving users without official patches or guidance.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from fundamental security weaknesses in Chargemap's WebSocket endpoints and API, such as a lack of proper authentication mechanisms, absence of rate limiting for authentication attempts, predictable and easily hijackable session identifiers, and publicly accessible charging station authentication identifiers. These design flaws make the system susceptible to various attacks, from impersonation and data manipulation to brute-force attacks and denial-of-service.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing Chargemap services should immediately assess their exposure and implement defensive measures, including minimizing network exposure of control systems, isolating them behind firewalls, and using secure remote access methods like updated VPNs. Given the vendor's unresponsiveness, businesses should contact Chargemap directly for remediation information and consider alternative solutions or enhanced monitoring for suspicious activity on their charging infrastructure. A thorough risk assessment and impact analysis should precede any defensive deployments.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-057-05</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Yokogawa CENTUM VP R6, R7]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">704ceb1d-2afe-4e89-9ec3-2320a88cce72</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Multiple vulnerabilities (CVE-2025-1924, CVE-2025-48019, CVE-2025-48020, CVE-2025-48021, CVE-2025-48022, CVE-2025-48023) have been identified in Yokogawa CENTUM VP R6 and R7, specifically affecting the Vnet/IP Interface Package. These vulnerabilities, with CVSS scores up to 6.9 (Medium severity), could allow an attacker to terminate software processes, cause denial-of-service, or execute arbitrary code through maliciously crafted packets.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing Yokogawa CENTUM VP R6 and R7 in critical infrastructure sectors such as Manufacturing, Energy, and Food and Agriculture face significant operational risks. Successful exploitation could lead to system downtime, disruption of industrial processes, and potential safety hazards, resulting in substantial financial losses and reputational damage.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from various weaknesses including out-of-bounds write, reachable assertion, integer underflow, and improper handling of length parameters within the Vnet/IP Interface Package. While these vulnerabilities are not remotely exploitable and have high attack complexity, they highlight the persistent challenge of securing complex industrial control systems against sophisticated attacks.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately apply the recommended patch software (R1.08.00) provided by Yokogawa and consult their advisory YSAR-26-0002 for detailed mitigation steps. Additionally, reinforce network segmentation, place control systems behind firewalls, and use secure remote access methods like updated VPNs to minimize exposure and potential attack vectors.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-057-09</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Pelco, Inc. Sarix Pro 3 Series IP Cameras]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">0806d04f-8f55-4c22-b825-4e7a6fce8018</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Pelco, Inc. Sarix Pro 3 Series IP Cameras (versions <=02.52) are vulnerable to an authentication bypass (CVE-2026-1241) in their web management interface. This flaw allows unauthorized access to live video streams and sensitive device data due to inadequate access control enforcement. The vulnerability has a CVSS v3 score of 7.5 (High severity).</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Successful exploitation can lead to significant privacy breaches, operational risks, and regulatory compliance issues for organizations utilizing these cameras. Businesses in critical infrastructure sectors, such as Commercial Facilities, Energy, and Healthcare, are particularly at risk of surveillance control bypass and data exposure. Reputational damage and potential financial penalties from non-compliance are also major concerns.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The root cause is an 'Authentication Bypass Using an Alternate Path or Channel' (CWE-288) within the camera's web management interface. This means the system fails to properly enforce authentication for certain functionalities, allowing attackers to access features without valid credentials. The flaw stems from inadequate security design or implementation in the access control mechanisms.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Organizations using affected Pelco Sarix Pro 3 Series IP Cameras must immediately update their camera firmware to version 02.53 or later to patch this vulnerability. Additionally, implement defensive measures such as minimizing network exposure, isolating control systems behind firewalls, and using secure VPNs for remote access. Conduct a thorough risk assessment to understand the specific impact on your infrastructure and ensure compliance.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-057-02</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Copeland XWEB and XWEB Pro]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2a336a96-c7f8-47ec-b454-3253aa522150</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Multiple critical vulnerabilities have been identified in Copeland XWEB and XWEB Pro versions <=1.12.1, impacting industrial control systems globally. These vulnerabilities, including authentication bypass, OS command injection, arbitrary file read, and buffer overflow, could allow attackers to gain unauthorized access, execute arbitrary code, and cause denial-of-service conditions.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing affected Copeland XWEB products face significant operational risks, including potential disruption of critical commercial facilities, data compromise, and system downtime. Exploitation could lead to severe financial losses, reputational damage, and regulatory penalties due to compromised industrial processes.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from insecure coding practices, such as improper handling of return values in authentication routines, insufficient neutralization of special characters in OS commands, and lack of proper input validation. These flaws allow attackers to manipulate system functions and bypass security controls.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately update all Copeland XWEB and XWEB Pro devices to the latest patched version as recommended by Copeland. Additionally, implement defense-in-depth strategies, including network segmentation, robust firewall rules, and restricting internet exposure for control system devices, to minimize attack surface and potential impact.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-057-10</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[EV Energy ev.energy]]></title>
      <category>Supply Chain/OT/ICS Security</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">aa19c19a-f710-4604-8a55-527fa13465fc</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <h3>What Happened?</h3>
        <p>Multiple critical and high-severity vulnerabilities have been identified in EV Energy's ev.energy charging station software, affecting all versions globally. These vulnerabilities could allow attackers to gain unauthorized administrative control over charging stations, impersonate legitimate chargers, or disrupt services through denial-of-service attacks.</p>
        
        <h3>Business Impact</h3>
        <p>Organizations utilizing EV Energy charging stations face significant operational risks, including service disruption, potential financial losses from unauthorized charging, and reputational damage due to compromised infrastructure. The lack of vendor response to CISA's coordination request exacerbates the risk, leaving users without immediate official patches.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Why It Happened</h3>
        <p>The vulnerabilities stem from fundamental security flaws such as missing authentication for critical functions, insufficient session expiration, improper restriction of excessive authentication attempts, and insufficiently protected credentials. These weaknesses in the WebSocket endpoints and API allow for various attack vectors, including session hijacking and brute-force attacks.</p>
        
        
        <h3>Recommended Executive Action</h3>
        <p>Immediately implement defensive measures, including isolating control system networks behind firewalls and minimizing internet exposure for all charging station devices. For remote access, mandate the use of secure VPNs, ensuring they are updated to the latest versions. Proactively contact EV Energy for updates on official patches and mitigation strategies.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/ics-advisories/icsa-26-057-07</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>